http://www.eastdurham.ac.uk/cookie_privacy_policy

Cookie & Privacy Policy
What are cookies?
Cookies are text files that are placed on your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. The cookie contains information that will help the website recognise your device next time you visit.
How are cookies used on the East Durham College website?
We use cookies to improve your experience of our website. Cookies are used to help you navigate between pages efficiently, remembering your preferences, and generally enhance the features for all users.
Should you wish to block or delete cookies from our website or any other website you can do this by changing your browser settings. Please see below for details.
Google Analytics
We use a web analytics service called Google Analytics to enable us to analyse how our website is used by visitors. Google Analytics cookies provide anonymous statistical data that shows usage trends to help us identify which content is most effective. These cookies record information such as the date and time of your visit, the type of browser you're using, your approximate geographic location and the URL of any page that led you to our web site.
If you do not want to be tracked by Google Analytics on the websites you visit you can opt out by follow these instructions from Google https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout
How cookies are classified
We have classified cookies on this site based on the categories and descriptions published in the International Chamber of Commerce (ICC) UK Cookie Guide
The East Durham College Privacy Policy
At East Durham College we wish for you to enjoy your visit to our website and understand and respect the need for privacy of your information. For your reassurance, the site makes every commitment to comply with GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation).
This privacy notice is issued by East Durham College. It is to inform applicants how their personal information will be used by the College. Your personal information is used by East Durham College to exercise its legal functions and meet its statutory responsibilities to provide education. Your information will be securely stored and securely destroyed after is it no longer required for these purposes, as detailed in the ICO GDPR document controller template. Your consent is required to capture, retain and process some of your personal data and you have the opportunity to opt-in to give consent.
This website is run by East Durham College and these guidelines are in relation to your data protection and relate solely to information provided by you via this website. Information you have supplied to us will only be used for the purposes for which you have provided it. In compliance with the Data Protection Act, your information will only be held for as long as necessary for these purposes.  Information may also be used to assess and analyse our services to you or to compile statistical reviews of the pages you have visited on our website. Again, all information will only be held for as long as necessary to fulfil these purposes.
We may from time to time send you information which we feel may be of interest to you. In many cases, this will be in reference to the course/subject area in which you have expressed an interest. We promise not to inundate you with marketing messages. We’ll always treat your personal data with the upmost care and will never sell or give them to other organisations for marketing purposes.
At the point of data collection we will give you the option to opt-in and tell us all the ways you’d be happy to hear from us, EG: By Post, Text, Telephone and Email.
Should you wish to change your communication preferences or have your data removed, please inform Student Services in writing by email: enquires@eastdurham.ac.uk or:
Student Services
East Durham College
Willerby Grove
Peterlee
County Durham
SR8 2RN
Livechat
We use live chat software on our website. This is provided by Click4Assistance, a 3rd party UK based Software Company. Information regarding how the data is processed and stored can be viewed here.
Sharing Information
We will not share your information for marketing purposes with other companies or organisations.
Data Security Statement
The College strives to take all reasonable steps to protect the data you disclose to us online but cannot guarantee its security fully. Visitors to the site who submit information must do so in compliance with accepting the security risks, and will not hold the College responsible for any breach of security.
Third Party Links
To provide a better service to you as a visitor to our site, where it is relevant, we will provide links to other websites which you may find useful or interesting. Responsibility for the information you provide to other such third party sites is with that site itself and not with the College.
These conditions are subject to change.
About The College
Term Dates
Open Days & Evenings
Prospectus & Course Guide Downloads
Open to the Public
College Facilities
College Virtual Tour
Virtual Open Evening Course Presentations
Elective Home Education
LEAP (formerly Engage Post-16)
Derwent ASC Provision
Our Careers Programme
Research Trials At The Houghall Campus
Training For The Unemployed
British Values
Spadework
History Of The Houghall Campus
History Of The Peterlee Campus
Useful Links
Venue Hire at East Durham College
College Management & Governance
Our Mission, Vision & ValuesOrganisational StructureCollege PrincipalStrategic Plan 2019 - 2022Governors & College GovernanceIntroduction To College Governance & GovernorsThe Role of the Governing BodyCommitteesMeetings, Agendas & MinutesGovernance DocumentsCurrent GovernorsBecoming A GovernorContact The Governing BodyStatement On Access To Meetings & MinutesWorking at East Durham CollegeApplying To Work At EDC - FAQsTalent Pool CVsStaff BenefitsTips For Applicants - Completing The Application FormTips For Applicants - Interview TechniquesTips For Applicants - Other Selection MethodsCollege PoliciesAdmission PolicyAnti-Bullying PolicyAppeals Against Assessment DecisionsBehaviour and Relationship Management PolicyBusiness Continuity PlanComplaints PolicyComputer Usage PolicyCoronavirus (COVID-19) Guidance PolicyData Breach Notification PolicyDisability PolicyDrugs PolicyEqual Opportunities PolicyExam Registration PolicyExternal Speakers PolicyFees PolicyGovernance Statement On AccessHealth & Safety PolicyInformation, Advice & Guidance Statement of ServiceInfringement Assessment RegulationsLearner Support Fund PolicyModern Slavery PolicyPrivacy Policy / Data ProtectionProvider Access Policy (Engage 14-16 Provision)Publication SchemeSafeguarding Of Young People & Vulnerable AdultsFreedom of Information PolicyGeneral Data Protection Regulations PolicyStudent CharterCollege CharterMembers' Report & Financial StatementEquality & Diversity Monitoring ReportEquality & Diversity Strategic TargetsEDC Gender Pay Gap ReportsPublic Value StatementPupil Premium StatementSubcontractor OpportunitiesGeneral Conditions Of Contract
CoursesAll CoursesView All CoursesA Levels Access to Higher EducationAccountancyAgricultureAnimal CareArt & DesignBeauty TherapyBrickworkBusiness & ManagementCarpentry & JoineryCatering & HospitalityChild & Adult CareComputing & ICTCounsellingCreative Media ProductionDistance LearningDog GroomingElectricalEngineeringEquineEssential SkillsFloristry & Floral DesignFoundation Studies (Houghall)Foundation Studies (Peterlee)Free Digital TrainingGCSEsHairdressing & BarberingHigher EducationHorticultureLEAP (Learn, Explore, Achieve, Progress)Land & Wildlife ManagementLand-Based Short CoursesMaths & English (Functional Skills)Motor VehicleMusic & Music TechnologyPainting & DecoratingPerforming ArtsPeter Jones Enterprise AcademyPhotographyPlumbing & GasPrince's Trust Team ProgrammeScienceSportsTeacher TrainingTravel & TourismTree Surgery & Forestry ManagementUniformed Public ServicesVeterinary NursingWeldingAll Peterlee Campus CoursesAll Houghall Campus CoursesAll Technical Academy CoursesA Levels (ED6 Sixth Form)Apply NowGCSEsMaths & English (Functional Skills)Access to Higher EducationHigher Education (Degree Level) CoursesDistance LearningE-LearningRequest a ProspectusSteps Into EmploymentCourse Fees InformationA Guide to QualificationsVocational Course Levels ExplainedVocational Grades & UCAS Tariff PointsCareers Advice ServiceCareers SearchCareerometerAbout EDCCollege InformationAbout East Durham CollegeTerm DatesOpen Days & EveningsProspectus & Course Guide DownloadsOpen To the PublicCollege FacilitiesTake a Virtual Tour of EDCHoughall Campus (Durham)The Technical AcademySports Performance CentresStudent Feedback ResultsStudent Progress SuccessHigh Grades SuccessA Level PerformancePositive DestinationsPositive Steps NurseryAbout Positive Steps NurseryFunding for Children at Positive Steps NurseryCurriculum at Positive Steps NurseryMeet the Staff - Positive Steps NurseryHigher Education SuccessFormer Student ProfilesActivities, Clubs & CompetitionsAttendanceUseful Info For ParentsOfsted Inspection ReportEngage (Pre-16) Direct RecruitmentEngage (Pre-16 Part-Time) School Referral ServiceElective Home EducationLEAP (Formerly Engage Post-16)Derwent ASC ProvisionOur Careers ProgrammeResearch Trials at HoughallBritish ValuesSpadeworkHistory of the Houghall CampusHistory of the Peterlee CampusUseful LinksVenue Hire at EDCEquine Facility HireHoughall Campus HireHire the Lubetkin TheatreMeeting Room HireSport Facility HireSupportSupporting YouFinancial SupportCourse FeesStudent Benefits Package (16-18)Guaranteed Bursary Scheme (16-18)Work Experience Subsidised TravelUniform, Kit and Equipment DiscountsFree Bus ServiceApprenticeshipsIntroduction to ApprenticeshipsRegister Your Interest in an ApprenticeshipCurrent Apprenticeship VacanciesWhy Become an Apprentice?How Do I Apply For An Apprenticeship?Apprenticeship TestimonialsThe Apprenticeship LevyParent's Apprenticeship FAQsEmployer's Apprenticeship FAQsEmployers - Useful Apprenticeship VideosEDC as an Apprenticeship Training ProviderHigher EdEmployersInformation for EmployersOur Careers Programme - Info For EmployersIndustrial PlacementsStudent Work Experience/PlacementsWorkplace LearningEmployer FeedbackEmployers - Could You Offer a Supported Internship?Free Digital Training for BusinessesLand Based Short Courses At HoughallManagement & LeadershipStaff Health & WellbeingStaff Recruitment ServiceApply
More Options
EventsNewsContact UsJobsCanvasE-LearningLocal SEND OfferOpen to the Public
Search
Search form
Search
